question what job most closely resembles
the job of Elliot from Mr Robot if you
can't tell I'm a pretty big Mr Robot fan
there may be references to Mr Robot in
this video right now if you look around
massive massive fan of Mr Robot I I feel
like uh it's one of the best things ever
created for many reasons it's also
extremely extremely rough to watch very
very adult themed and not for the
average child please do not let your
children watch Mr Robot but if you're
just wondering about getting a job like
Elliot or being cool uh like Elliott uh
fun fact that poster is actually from Dr
Strange Love which I learned on the
stream somebody said hey you have a
Doctor Strange Love poster I'm no I have
a Mr Robot poster I'm like no you don't
you have a Doctor Strange Love poster
turns out we were both right anyway huge
Elliott fan um I'm not going to give any
spoilers away police don't give any
spoilers but to tell you the truth um
the closest job to what Elliott is doing
first of all what La was doing is
illegal and he did it on the side uh and
also it depends on what point in his
career you're asking the question right
it was it you know before he destroyed
the world or after and that's a little
bit of a spoiler but pretty obvious um
so the question is he worked for a
company called um God I forget the name
now uh he worked for that security
company with that one
guy right uh and evil he he worked for
evil Corp so he so he worked for evil
Corp and he also worked
at allsafe there I remembered he worked
at allsafe okay you're being on you're
all on the video everybody I'm just
warning you because you're going in
YouTube video thank you for your
comments we'll get to him so so when
Elliot was working at Alla he was
security consultant he was literally a
security analyst and if you want to know
about that job you can go to the Bureau
of Labor and statistics. goov and you
can go over here and search for
security uh this is America but you know
and here is the occupational handbook
about the job this is Elliott's job
right here Elliot was doing this
security Analyst job and he was by the
way this is the fastest growing Tech
Career in the entire list of careers so
it is the closest thing to his job but I
think it's important that I remind you
that Elliot didn't like his
job right I don't want to give too much
away but he didn't ellot did not like
his job at
ala
and um that's all I'm I really can't say
more otherwise we're going to don't
nobody spoil
it um Elliot was not a job script about
he does talk about developing a
JavaScript in HTML at one point but that
was not it um so but there is it's
important that you talk there's another
there's another career path that Elliot
was following on the side and that job
is called a
pentester or a red team security person
um if you search for hacker jobs um you
won't find them but if you are going to
search for jobs if if you need to search
terms to find jobs that are like Elliott
is Elliot ARR he actually probably would
have been um so if you look for jobs
that match what Elliott did at least at
either on this side as a hacker or well
he worked for EP society which
technically he worked for them right and
where you're looking for his all safe
you know happy job then you're looking
for security analyst you're looking for
pentester you're looking for red team
you're looking for blue team you're
looking for computer security
forensics um you're looking for computer
engineer uh it just depends on the thing
about Elliot is he's fictional right but
he was good at everything so I mean you
know he hacked that one system with a
Raspberry Pi which we won't talk about
right he took a Raspberry Pi and he
hacked a physical system using the
raspberry pi um he was also you know a
network analyst in fact uh Elliot
thwarts one of the attacks from a hacker
um um that is you know using the network
congestion and stuff like that to do
sort of denial of service so network
engineer uh and you know this gets into
another thing that I kind of concluded
in another video related to the beginner
boost you know it's not always about
security is kind of everywhere right so
if you want to do the kind of things
Elliot does when the music gets really
intense and he the the he gets zoned in
and and there's like this is what I live
for to directly quote Elliott sorry for
this s it I live for this [__] you know
and he's like taing away his keyboard
fast as he can he actually not he's like
finger typing a nano sometimes there is
a
million there are a million little tiny
nods in Mr Robot to the actual
programmers out there
including uh one very glaring one which
I may have posted to a Reddit about this
one where he's coding in Python and he
deliberately codes in P something that's
only in Python 2 and something that's
only in Python 3 and the lines are one
right after the other one and the only
people who would notice that are people
who freeze framed on the code and who
actually know how to code in Python and
they would look at that and they would
go oh okay so the writers who actually
know what they're doing most of the time
they actually put that in there as kind
of a wink wink to the other coders out
there like your yourself so yeah and and
Elliot cro cloes in Pearl he cloes in
Python he tends to prefer Ruby for his
code which is fine metas and stuff most
of that's Ruby He codes He codes in C
obviously um you do see assembly on
occasion on the screen but uh if we were
GNA what I really wanted to see is I
wanted to see what Darlene coded in
Darlene is the malware chick and she
would have been really fun to to see
what she coded uh almost all the code
though is either python or
um and and so if you want to learn a
language if you want to be like Elliot
um that those would be the the things to
go there um what are the differences
between red and blue team uh red or
defense I'm sorry blue is defense red is
attack and knowing how to defend your
system and how to attack a system um you
have to stay tuned for other videos I I
have defended myself against hackers I
have been hacked I have caught hackers
and submitted them to the authorities
before I have hacked multiple systems
which I can't talk about most of the
time by the way if you want to hack
systems and get paid for it that's pent
that's pent testing you either work for
the government or you work for an
organization that finds bugs and Bug
Bounty there's another key word bug
bounties and you submit that in in fact
bug Bounty searching for bugs in a bug
Bounty kind of way is the closest thing
uh to the official professional term for
that would be red teaming that you know
pen testing penetration testing um and
sometimes it's physical security it's
not just it's not just software but if
you wanted to do something like Elliot
when he was attacking people the closest
thing to that is probably bug Bounty and
probably zero day discovery which is you
know forensics and things like that a
zero day is a vulnerability in a piece
of software or anything really that has
not yet been detected by anybody else
and there's actually really great videos
on that you can watch the cyber War
documentary which is absolutely
outstanding and it goes into this kind
of thing there's actually one team that
talks about what they do with their zero
days there's another guy who lives in a
gated community in Las Vegas um who
talks about his zero days he's
discovered um if you find a zero day I
mean if I were to do to go into computer
security that's what I would do if I I
would I would work on zero day Discovery
and I would work on um which is
basically quality assurance know the
kind of thing that you would have to do
on your software to make sure it was
safe right well if you're doing that
level and you're trying to find holes in
existing software if you actually manage
to find a really significant hole you
can be paid multiple millions of dollars
depending on how bad the zero day is so
stucks net one of the most famous uh
piece hacks of all time which the
Israeli government and the Americans
finally came out and said they made they
created it um and it's documented out
there you can go watch it they denied it
for years for years years and years and
years they denied it and now the people
who made it openly say yeah we made that
back and when and uh it actually
contained think three or four zero days
um just to get it to work so a zero day
is a vulnerability that that nobody
knows about and if you're the only one
who knows about it obviously you have an
immense amount of power and Pen testing
is not finding zero days you might find
a zero day but more likely you're going
to find that somebody hasn't updated
their software and you need to tell
about it and shame them into doing it by
making them give you money not through
extortion but that guy got got caught by
the way did you guys see the news on
that yeah uh it said he was hired as a
pentester at a nuclear power plant nice
yeah it's actually not hard to be hired
as a pentester pentesting is
ridiculously easy most pentesting is
like run all of these scripts against
this system and write a report it's very
boring and and it's not the kind of
that's pen testing like that is kind of
Elliott's alls saafe day job that he
hated he hated because all he's doing is
just you know running scripts against
things all the time and they're checking
for vulnerabilities I mean I can almost
quote the the boss what he tells him
when he I thought we had scripts to
prevent these things from happening you
know because because it's such a boring
job all you're doing is you're just
tracking the known vulnerabilities
database and and checking out all of
your clients to make sure that they're
not susceptible to it the only
difference between that and Bug Bounty
is that when you're doing bug Bounty
you're doing that against companies that
have agreed to pay money if you actually
find something versus working for a
company like allsafe that has clients
that they are protecting and they're
pretty much just dedicated to pentesting
their systems for them and keeping them
safe so that and that's and that's where
Red and Blue and and all that come in um
so uh they're called Script kitties yeah
script Kitty
pent most this is kind of where I was
going with this most pentesting is just
script Kitty work seriously there's
already a rootkit that's going to do
everything you want to do um you know
these people call themselves hackers who
are lachic denial of service attacks
which just floods systems with tons of
traffic that takes no brain cells
whatsoever it's like it's not it's it
they they then they you know get all
tattooed and you know listen to like
skrillix or some [__] and and then they
think they're is Big Time hacker the big
time hackers if you want to be an actual
big-time hacker find a zero day find a
zero day learn how to find a zero day
learn how to analyze software for
vulnerabilities and find those zero days
the real kickass hackers the ones who
are over 9,000 are the ones who actually
find the zero days and prevent others
from finding zero days um and those are
the people who are going to do that kind
of thing um we don't know whether
whether Elliot actually Elliot does find
several zero days because he has to find
vulnerabilities in the organizations
that he's attacking and he has to work
around stuff so in a sense he's kind of
a zero day you know badass if you will
um but but you know most of this in fact
he he he yells at Darlene for making
software that almost gets him detected
because malare because because she um
just grabs it from from B Bolton board
and puts it in because it's just you
know some she what we script Kitty and
that's where the term script Kitty comes
from um so yeah if you want that job if
you want if you want Elliot's job uh you
got to learn Linux you got to learn how
to code you got to learn a lot of the
stuff that I go over in the beginner
boost but but more importantly you need
to learn to think outside the box you
need to learn to think like a hacker and
that's where this video is it's under
the learn to think like a hacker section
that's all